Ankit Bhatia

Profile

15 years experienced passionate frontend developer with proven technical and organizational skills seeking a challenging position in your organization.

With strong analytical, coding, leadership and problem solving expertise, I look forward to scale my career in Tech Leadership roles.

Employment History

Senior Frontend Developer - II (Principal Engineer), Novorise Fintech Pvt Ltd, Gurugram

09/2021 - Present

- Company's revenue increased by \$200,000 in the first month of launch, with Express ACH feature built by me in core banking division.
- Enabled small business by developing Novo Funding feature, where Novo, in first 6months, had loaned approx 10million USD to its end users.
- Lead the frontend development of Debit card feature including user facing application as well as Novo Administrator portal, which is generating 60% of the revenue for novo and is the most critical core banking feature for the organization.
- Outside project I am leading the team responsible for JS to TS migration, and, identifying & fixing security vulnerabilities in the web apps.
- Built the APIs from scratch in Admin portal for Card Management System using NodeJS, graphql and postgres
- Tech Skills: ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, GraphQL, Tailwind, Postgres, Webpack, Github, JIRA, Javascript

Frontend Lead, Epsilon Conversant, Bengaluru

12/2019 - 09/2021

- Lead & Managed multiple teams of 5-7 developers each simultaneously.
- Reduced the overall development time by building processes for frontend team and aligned the development process in sync with AEM.
- Brought impact in Digital Division by developing internal tools for sales & management dept. using MERN Stack, which were later showcased to bid for external projects.
- I was the representative for and acted as a manager between the frontend team and the client
- Tech Skills: ReactJS, Javascript, LESS, NodeJS, AEM, JIRA, Github, HTML, CSS, Storybooks, Webpack, Gulp

Technical Lead, TEKSystems, Bengaluru

05/2019 - 12/2019

- Lead & mentored a team of 3 developers.
- Had to communicate with client directly for the status updates, work progress and project estimations and timelines.
- Established code reviews process and helped reducing technical debt by 30%
- Tech Skills: Javascript, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, Github

Sr. Interactive Developer, Sapient Consulting, Gurugram

02/2014 - 05/2019

Personal Details

A-1/75, Sector - 5, Rohini Delhi, 110085 India +91 999 040 6652 ankit.bhatia87@gmail.com

Courses

Practical GitHub Copilot, LinkedIn Learning

11/2023 - 11/2023

The Ultimate Photography Course in Post-Processing & Editing, Udemy

05/2023 - 05/2023

Learning Node.js, Linkedin Learning

08/2021 - 08/2021

TypeScript: Object-Oriented Programming, LinkedIn Learning

07/2020 - 07/2020

Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/bhatia87

https://github.com/ankitbhatia87

https://www.ankitbhatia.com/

Skills

HTML5

CSS 3

Javascript

ReactJS

Redux

NodeJS

- Built the web apps for MFS and Fidelity UK from scratch.
- Directly managed client communication, and, was involved in planning, grooming and development phases.
- Demonstrated efficient use of Agile which got recognized at client side.
- Helped increase overall traffic by developing new features in Personal Investor division.
- Single-handedly worked on creating the components in AEM while working on the MFS webapp.
- Tech Skills: ReactJS, Javascript, LESS, SCSS, NodeJS, AEM, jQuery, JIRA, Github, HTML, CSS, Angular 2, BackboneJS, Grunt, Gulp

Lead Engineer, HCL Technologies, Noida

04/2011 - 01/2014

- Singlehandedly managed the frontend of client's web app with 100% billability.
- Introduced jQuery in the projects for building advanced features and better animations in the app.
- Developed plugins like accordion, image carousels, floating popups, infinity tabs, etc. using jQuery.
- Tech Skills: jQuery, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Github

Software Development Engineer, Treystaa Services, Delhi

08/2009 - 12/2010

- Brought a significant value add to the product by building the reports feature in it using jQuery and actionscript 3.
- Helped product owners in creating interactive video demos using actionscript 3 for marketing and promotional activities in Adobe Flash.
- Tech Skills: jQuery, Javascript, Actionscript 3.0, HTML, CSS, Adobe Flash, Adobe Photoshop

Web Designer, Vinove Software & Services, Delhi

07/2008 - 07/2009

- I was able to convert 3-4 PSDs in 1 day apparantly increasing the revenue of the company
- Trained junior web designers in developing the webpages from scratch using XHTML, CSS and javascript.
- Later I took charge of the frontend for invoicing and money management products and scaled them from PoCs to revenue generation products.
- Tech Skills: HTML, CSS, Adobe Photoshop, PHP, SVN

Education

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, Sikkim Manipal University

08/2004 - 01/2008

Extra Curricular Activities

Volunteer, Sameer Foundation, Delhi

04/2013 - 02/2018

- Volunteer for teaching under privileged students. Taught basics of computer.
- Administrative volunteer to organize trips to historical places for under privileged students. Took them to places like Taj Mahal, Doll Museum, Rail Museum, Qutub Minar etc.

SCSS, LESS, Tailwind

Grunt, Gulp, Webpack

RESTApi, GraphQL

MongoDb, Postgres

Agile (Scrum)

Effective Communication

Team Management

Hobbies

Photography, History, Geopolitics and Reading

Languages

Hindi

English